BILLTHAN

Bachelor of Information Candidate | https://www.billthan.ca

I am an undergraduate student pursuing a Bachelor of Information at the University of Toronto. I have over 4+ years of coding experience. As an experienced lifeguard and supervisor staff, I am a confident leader who thrives in team scenarios. I thrive in large scale projects that require the use of Human-Centered Design and Interaction principles. I am currently interested in research pertaining to Human-Centered Data Science (HCDS) and Human Computer Interaction (HCI)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NORMERICA Incorporated

Software Testing Intern | January 2020 - March 2020

- Re-structured 10 years worth of user accounting data for migration
- Verified 10 years worth of user accounting data in new system for accuracy

Revealed at least 50+ fatal faults in SQL server to prevent user frustration

- Improved server efficiency with careful documentation

City of Toronto

Aquatic In-Charge & Trainer | June 2018 - present

- Restructured aquatic trainings to adhere to COVID-19 procedures
- Increased aquatic staff efficiency with effective training materials
- Confidently lead and directed swim instructors in aquatic programs
- Improved workplace efficiency with careful official documentation

PERSONAL PROJECTS

BigWeather (Java, Windows)

Interactive Windows Weather Statistical Analysis tool

- Securely handled diverse API and key encryption in Java
- Efficiently deserialize raw JSON/XML metadata
- Used HCI principles to facilitate easy-to use GUI

Hackintosh Development (HP G1 800, XPS 9500)

Open source, EFIs for running macOS on non-Apple devices

- Maintain 50+ kernels, driver files, and config.plist
- Rigorously tested each peripheral to ensure driver compatibility
- Maintain 40+ drivers for stability

Natural Nails and Spa Website (HTML, CSS, .js)

https://www.naturalnailsspa.ca

- Redesigned website every year since 2015
- Monthly website maintenance
- Monthly SEO reports for client

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Information (BI)

User Experience and Human Centered Data Science 2018-2022

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Mathematics, Computer Science, and Education 2018-2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

University of Toronto \$5000 Scholarship (2020)
Ontario Student \$5000 Grant (2020)

HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN SKILLS

User Research

Prototyping

Agile/Iterative Design

User Journey Mapping

Usability Testing

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

python Java

Kotlin JSON/XML

RStudio HTML5/CSS3

C/C++

JavaScript

SQL

Human Centered Design Tools

Figma Adobe CC
LaTeX markdown

BALSAMIQ